Yuliet García

Phone: +52 461 145 35 25

Email: yuliet.garciapuente@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://YulyGP.github.io/portfolio

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

QA Manual tester skilled at test planning, writing test cases, test execution, bug logging, and test status reporting. Experienced in manual testing of web and mobile applications in an Agile software development work environment. Excellent technical communication, documentation, interpersonal, and reporting skills. Motivated hard worker with a professional attitude and work ethic. Ability to handle multiple tasks and work independently as well as in a team.

SKILLS

- Agile and Waterfall Methodologies
- Jira and Xray-for-Jira
- Test cases creation
- Desktop apps testing
- Mobile apps testing
- Web apps testing
- APIs testing
- Bug report
- Markdown
- GitBook

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2022 - present

QA Lead

NexxtMission. Freelance. USA/Mexico

Responsibilities:

- Coordinated and directed QA Testing efforts in an Agile sprint-based/kanban-based methodology.
- Collaborated with product managers and developers to define workflow procedures and manage Agile boards as well as process improvements.
- Work with QA automation team to plan and prioritize automation for various front ends, APIs and services.
- Designed and executed test cases manually using black box and grey box testing techniques for web-based and mobile applications in QA, pre-production, and production environments.
- Trained new testers, both in-house and off-shore, in the QA methodology and the products used by our team and end-user companies.
- Document testing procedures, methodologies, or criteria.
- UI testing with Cypress and APIs testing with Postman.

QA Manual Tester

Nexxtway. Freelance. Guadalajara, Mexico

Responsibilities:

- Created test cases and performed regular, scheduled testing on all the apps, as well as websites we developed as a company.
- Implementation of QA Methodologies for mobile and web applications.
- Attending and coordinating team meetings, Daily Scrum meetings, Sprint Planning, and Retrospective meetings.
- Proficient in QA testing using tools like JIRA and Monday.com.
- UI testing with Cypress and APIs testing with Postman.
- Write technical documentation and create tasks for developers.

08/2019 - 06/2020

English Language Teacher Continente Americano University. Guanajuato, Mexico

03/2015 - 06/2019

Archivist and Quality Assurance specialist CIFO-Veigas Archive. Havana, Cuba

10/2014 - 03/2015

Communications Executive ACTUAR Artistic Agency for Performing Arts. Havana, Cuba

09/2011 - 10/2014

Information Specialist Universidad de La Habana. Havana, Cuba

EDUCATION

2006 - 2011

Bachelor's Degree in Librarianship and Information Science, Universidad de La Habana. Havana, Cuba. Thesis: During my studies, I discovered a passion for technology which led me to be involved in a thesis that, along with other tasks and methodologies validation, requires me to design and perform multiple tests on a website. As a result, I detected several bugs and improvements and then worked with the development team to create a better version of that website.